Guide to the Oral History of the American Left: Radical Histories Collection OH 002
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- D
  - Name: Dean, Jeannette Description: Background; union activities; radicalism and unions, UE in Newark., Apr 14, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Name: De Leon, Solon Description: Socialist Party and reformism, 1900-20; Solon's break with Daniel DeLeon; IWW; Industrial Union League and Socialist Labor Party since 1930s., Dec 16, 1972 (Box 1)
    tape#: 3 U2F
  - Name: Delfino, Albina Description: Italian-American women and the Communist Party, Needle Trades Industrial Union, National Textile Workers Union; CP organizer in Lawrence, Providence, Boston, Corona, N.Y., 1930s-40s., Jan 8, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Name: Dolgoff, Esther Description: Anarchist women of the 1930s; character of anarchism., Jan 27, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Name: Dongas, Bill Description: Greek partisan in WWII; immigration struggles in 1950s; Greek publications and radio-Chicago., Apr 3, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Dora Description: Student radicalism, 1930s; Communist Party; United Electrical Workers; social life and friends., Mar 25, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Name: Dougherty, Pauline Description: Background in shoe town; college politics in depression; union activity in offices and the Left; McCarthy Era; reflections., Jan-82 (Box 1)
    tape#: 4 U2G
  - Name: Drake-Raphals, Susan Description: Workers Party, 1940s and her role in it; C.L.R. James in the 1940s., May 7, 1983 (Box 1)
    tape#: 2 U2G
  - Name: Draper, Hal Description: Role as editor of Labor Action, 1949-1958; problems of "Shachtmanite" group and analysis offered in LA; developing writers and subjects for newspaper; political disintegration of group; Draper moves to Berkeley., Nov 5, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Duda, Walter Description: Lithuanian-American Left activities around Connecticut's Brass Valley, 1920s-50s., Mar 15, 1983 (Box 1)
    tape#: 1 U2G
  - Name: Dudley, Jane Description: Dance and left politics; New Dance group; Martha Graham; civil rights., 1981 (Box 1)
  - Name: Dunayevskaya, Raya Description: Trotsky and Trotskyism, 1930s; Johnson- Forest group, 1940s; coal strikes of 1949-50 and origins of "Marxist-Humanist" organization News and Letters., Mar 24, 1983 (Box 1)
- E
  - Name: Edwards, George Description: Political origins as Garveyite, 1920s; social life in 1920s-30s; semiprofessional football player, prohibition-era gangster, factory worker; Communist organizer, Kansas-Nebraska district, 1930s-40s; disillusionment in Communist movement, Oakland, Ca., 1940s-50s; life in Ghana, 1950s-60s., Nov 4, 1983 (Box 1)
    tape#: 3 U2G
  - Name: Edwards, Herb Description: Life in Wisconsin lumber, early 1900s and Industrial Workers of the World; Elmer Smith, repression of IWW; San Quentin; IWW ebb., Feb 12, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Name: Edwards, Hoddee Description: Background in Boston Jewish community, 1920s-30s; Communist activist in California, 1940s; women's rights crusader, People's World, 1949; life in Ghana, 1950s-60s; private life since., Nov 12, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Epstein, Melech Description: Recollections of experiences since his immigration from Warsaw in 1913, including editorship of Freiheit; comments on Yiddish publications and Jewish life in America, the Cold War, Israel, and current (early 1970s) American politics., Jan 9, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Name: Epstein, Virginia Description: Born 1885; background in Dallas, Texas as child of mixed Episcopalian-Jewish marriage; in New York from 1908, Socialist Party, 1910s; Communist Party from 1920s; American Council on US-Soviet Friendship; Committee of American Women; local political activities in Queens, N.Y., Mar 30, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Evelyn, S. Description: Youth in Connecticut and the Bronx; Young Communist League, 1930s; anti-Nazi and pro-Republican Spain activity in Yorkville., Jun 25, 1982 (Box 1)
- F
  - Name: Faber, Seymour Description: Radical Zionism; Johnson-Forest Tendency; Detroit 1930s-60s., Mar 30, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Felhaber, Elmer Description: Minnesota newspaper unionism, 1930s; CIO and Communist Party; Ohio Left after WWII; visits abroad., 2/5/1981 (Box 1)
    tape#: 2 U2H
  - Name: Ferguson, Duncan Description: (Memorial Meeting) Eulogy by Harry Ring, of sculptor and activist in Socialist Workers Party, 1940s-70s., 1975 (Box 1)
  - Name: Ferlinghetti, Lawrence Description: Beat Generation in retrospect; San Francisco avant-garde arts and anarchism, 1940s and early 1950s; formation of City Lights book- store and publishing company; tasks for artists in modern world., Dec-81 (Box 1)
  - Name: Figueredo, Joseph Description: Portuguese-American Left in New Bedford and Fall River, Mass., 1930s-40s; political origins in strikes of 1920s and Communist role; lack of formal fraternal and cultural structure and absence of regular Portuguese- language Communist press; use of local radio; Cold War pressures, 1940s, and departure to San Francisco; activities in ILWU, 1950s-present., Nov 3, 1983 (Box 1)
    tape#: 4 U2H
  - Name: Fisher, Morris Description: Labor Zionism and Workmen's Circle, 1930s; Jewish Socialist Farband, led by L. Siegel with Fisher as assistant; Israel and Yiddish; Miami Beach Yiddishkayt today., Mar 16, 1983 (Box 1)
    tape#: 1 U2H
  - Name: Foner, Henry Description: Driven out of teaching, late 1940s; industry and union activities, 1948-present; Communist Party and Ben Gold., Mar 29, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Name: Friedland, William Description: Cultural perspective in Workers Party; role of music in Friedland's life and creation of record, Songs for Sectarians; college teaching and sympathy for antiwar students, 1960s., May 6, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Friedland, Isadore & Fishgold Max Description: Union activities and the Left, 1930s- 1950s., Mar 15, 1983 (Box 1)
- G
  - Name: Gale, Mary Description: Growing up in East New York and Queens in 1910s-20s; ILGWU, 1920s-30s; Scottsboro case, American Labor Party; family and home life in relation to her work and political activism., Jan 29, 1982 (Box 1)
    tape#: 3 U2H
  - Name: Gardners, Alex & Faye; Kantor, Abe & Hodes, Hyman Description: Jewish and Italian radicalism, 1930s-1950s; Unemployed councils; Workers' Club; WPA; Garibaldi Clubs; work with Marcantonio as his campaign manager, union activities., Mar 15, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Garlin, Sender Description: Personal background in Socialist Party, 1910s; working at the Daily Worker, 1920s-30s; atmosphere of newspaper; role of humor at Daily Worker., Oct 14, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Name: Gellert, Hugo Description: Cartoonist adn graphic artist. Immigration from Hungary to US, and return of John Reed; cartoonist, Masses magazine; commercial work for New Yorker and New York newspapers, 1920s-30s; role as cartoonist in Hungarian-American Left newspaper, Uj Elore., Apr 4, 1984 (Box 1)
    tape#: 3 U2I
  - Name: Gerson, Sophie Melvin Description: Background and youth in the Ukraine, Massachusetts, New York; Young Communist League, 1920s; Passaic and Gastonia textile strikes., Mar 26, 1976 (Box 1)
    tape#: ?
  - Name: Giganti. Joseph Description: Italian-American Communist newspaper, Il Lavoratore, editorial staff and theatrical commentary; nature of Italian-American Left milieu in Chicago, 1920s; expulsion from Communist movement; early Trotskyism; "Oehlerite" faction of Trotskyists, and their Chicago activity, 1930s; expulsion from Ohelerites and further political commitments., Jul 26, 1983 (Box 1)
    tape#: 2 U2I
  - Name: Gitlin, Todd Description: Students for a Democratic Society, 1960, Mar 1, 1970 (Box 1)
    tape#: 1 U2I
  - Name: Gittings, Barbara Description: Gay liberation movement, 1950s-70s, Jul 26, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Glaberman, Jessie Description: Socialist Workers Party and Workers Party in New York, Philadelphia and Detroit, 1930s-1950s., Aug 17, 1977-Sep 3, 1977 (Box 1)
    tape#: 7 U2I
  - Name: Glaberman, Martin Description: Johnson-Forest Tendency; New York and Detroit, 1940s-50s., Mar 29, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Glassman, Ruth Description: American Youth Congress, 1930s; WWII and shop agitation; women in factories, United Electrical Workers; struggles and problems., Feb 1, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Name: Glotzer, Albert Description: Family background in Russia and Chicago; Communist Party, 1920s; American Trotskyism, late 1920s-30s; Workers Party, 1940s., Dec 13, 1983 (Box 1)
    tape#: 4 U2I
  - Name: Gold, Lillian Description: Socialist Party, War Resisters' League, FDR & trade unions, union activity, Apr 4, 1982 (Box 1)
    tape#: 2 U2J
  - Name: Goldberg, Itche Description: Immigration and Canadian Yiddish background; Left Yiddishkayt in New York, 1920s-30s; struggle for autonomy wihin Communist framework; Yiddish pedagogy versus politics; reflections., Jun 5, 1982 (Box 1)
    tape#: 1 U2J
  - Name: Goldberg, Itche Description: Jewish cultural movement, and role of her humor in Jewish cultural life., Feb 17, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Goldstein, Mollie Description: Communist Party, 1930s; women's organizations; price and rent protests, Brooklyn and the Bronx., Nov 7, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Name: Goldstein, Nina Description: Early life in Russia, Canada; work and political life in Brownsville and East Flatbush, Brooklyn, 1920s-30s; Communist Party, Freiheit, International Workers Order; Russian War Relief and aid to Israel, 1940s; Jewish cultural movement, Miami Beach., Mar 19, 1980 (Box 1)
    tape#: 4 U2J
  - Name: Goldwater, Walter Description: On C.L.R. James, 1920s-60s; Workers Party, 1940s; Trotskyism, anti-Stalinism, neo-conservatism, Pan-Africanism; Eric Williams., Feb 15, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Gordon, Michael Description: Frontier Films, Film and Photo League, 1930s; Group Theatre; Brecht's influence; film work., Mar 25, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Name: Grandma was an Activist Description: Radio series on women radicals of 1930s, in six half-hour parts, produced from OHAL interviews for WBAI-FM; includes excerpts from interviews with Louise Thompson, Jane Dudley, Alice Dodge Wolfson, Meridel LeSueur et. al., 1983 (Box 1)
    tape#: 3 U2J
  - Name: Grant, Leah-Dillon Description: Yiddish literary milieu in 1920s and role of interviewee's uncle, A.M. Dillon; Johnson-Forest Tendency, its leaders and activities, 1940s; cultural perspectives., Jul 24, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Greenberg, Samuel Description: Yiddish culture and the Left; Los Angeles Yiddish Left from the 1930s-present., Oct 27, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Name: National Guardian Forum Description: New Communist Party; criticism of 1960s' politics; history of the class struggle., May 26, 1905 (Box 1)
- H
  - Name: Halonen, Oive Description: Finnish-American radicalism, Minnesota and Oregon, 1910s-30s; participation in Spanish Civil War as member of Abraham Lincoln Brigade; experiences as Seattle machinist, 1940s-60s., Feb 27, 1978 (Box 1)
    tape#: 1 U2K
  - Name: Hanusiak, Michael Description: Ukrainian-American Left; International Workers Order, 1930s-40s; effect of McCarthyism; problems of organization, publication and generational continuity in the ethnic progressive movement today., Mar 30, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Harap, Louis Description: Harvard University, 1930s; Jewish Survey, 1940s; Jewish Life, 1940s-50s; Rosenberg case; Jewish Currents 1950s-70s., Mar 19, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Name: Harrington, Michael Description: "Prehistory" of Students for a Democratic Society, late 1950s; SDS, 1960s., Oct 6, 1969 (Box 1)
    tape#: 6 U2K
  - Name: Hartquist, Daniel Description: Socialist movement in Sweden and Swedish- American Socialism; Left in New England, 1930s-40s; reflections on American Communism., Feb 5, 1981 (Box 1)
    tape#: 2 U2K
  - Name: Henry, James B. Description: Legal prosecution of the International Workers Order in New York State, 1950s. Ex-Special Assistant Attorney General, May 11, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Name: Hood, Otis Description: Union family background; New England Left in 1930s; Communist Party in Vermont, 1930s; Communist Party in Boston, 1930s-40s; prison experience; reflections., Mar 25, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Name: Hoopes, Walter Description: St. Louis Free Thought, nineteenth century to 1940s; personal background in Germany, immigration to US, Rand School; Socialist Party in St Louis, 1930s; Free Thought (atheism) in St Louis, 1940s-present., Oct 6, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Name: Horzen, Frank Description: Politics in Fontana, California; by member of religious (anti-socialist) South Slav benefit association and steel worker, later mayor of Fontana; attitude toward Henry Kaiser and toward later (Third World) immigrants., Oct 26, 1982 (Box 1)
- I
  - Name: International Ladies' Garment Workers Union Description: 11 anonymous women and men, 1910-30s, struggles between left and right, 1974-1977 (Box 1)
    tape#: 9 U2L
  - Name: International Labor Defense Description: David Freeman, Sam Neuberger, and Fay Pasternak on ILD, National Lawyers Guild and radical legal work, 1930s-40s; recollections of Joe Brodsky, Carol King, Vito Marcantonio, and others., Jun 12, 1982 (Box 1)
    tape#: 3 U2L
- J
  - Name: Jakubka, S.J. Description: Background in Lithuania; activities in Argentina, 1930s; editorship of Vilnis, Chicago Lithuanian-language newspaper, since 1942; problems of publishing ethnic newspaper; role of cultural activities in Lituanian-American movement., Jul 28, 1983 (Box 1)
    tape#: 1 U2L
  - Name: Jewish People's Chorus Description: Excerpt from performance at Yablon Center, Los Angeles., Apr 14, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Name: Johnson, Howard Description: Harlem show business in 1930s; Cotton Club and dancing; politicization; joins CP; community involvement, 1940s; Jackie Robinson, Paul Robeson; blacks and whites in the Communist Party. Sound reel from his night class, Oct 17, 1979 (Box 1)
- K
  - Name: Kaartinen, Ohni Description: Finnish-American radical background, 1930s; Spanish Civil war; fraternal and political activities, 1940s-present., Jul 7, 1984 (Box 1)
    tape#: 2 U2L
  - Name: Kaplan, Morris Description: YKUF, L.A. Jewish cultural movement, Jul 15, 1984 (Box 1)
    tape#: 1 U2M
  - Name: Katz, Maud White Description: Early days in CP, fight against white chauvinism; Needle Trades Industrial Union, 1920s., Oct 18, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Name: Kempf, Ed Description: N.J. Regional Director, Steel Workers Organizing Committee-Harrison-Hoboken- Jersey City, Crucible Steel-Otis Elevator, Socialist Party and Socialist Workers Party, 1930s., Oct 29, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Name: Kertman, Aaron Description: YKUF, L.A. Jewish Cultural Movement, Apr 7, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Name: Kerzic, Anton Description: Origins of Slovenian-American fraternal movement in Waukegan and North Chicago, Illinois; Kerzic as a worker in a cooperative grocery store, 1930s-40s; work with Finnish-American fraternal group in milk co-op, 1930s-50s; midwestern SNPJ and conflict with eastern SNPJ; Kerzic as founder of present savings and loan bank, Waukegan., Jul 27, 1983 (Box 1)
    tape#: 2 U2M
  - Name: Kish, Maurice Description: Brief interview with Russian-born painter about his family and his work., Feb 17, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Camp Kinderland Reunion Description: Reminiscences; reading of letters; songs and dances., Jun 9, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Name: Kolehmainen, Mary Description: Immigration to America; life in Finnish-American Left; activities of Finns in Boston area, 1930s-40s; role as editor of women's weekly Naisten Viiri; support of Finnish-American movement., Mar 10, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Name: Kolehmainen, Mary Description: Immigration to America; life in Finnish-American Left; activities of Finns in Boston area, 1930s-40s; role as editor of women's weekly Naisten Viiri; support of Finnish-American movement., Jul 30, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Korn, Joseph Description: YKUF, L.A. Jewish Cultural Movement, Apr 16, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Koski, Ernest Description: Finnish-American Left in Mesabi Iron Range; Cooperatives; Tyomies newspaper., Jul 31, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Kravitz, Nettie Description: Johnson-Forest Tendency, radical feminism, East Coast & Detroit, 40s-60s, Apr 1, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Kryzak, Rose Description: Growing up in NYC, her life as a CP member in 1933, her trip to Soviet Union and impressions of it, CP and women issues, the McCarthy period., Jan 4, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Name: Kunin, Jacob Description: Ethnic groups and politics, Bridgeport, Connecticut, 1920s-40s., Mar 2, 1967 (Box 1)
- L
  - Name: Lahusen, Kay Description: Gay liberation movement, 1950s-70s; relationship between gay movement and the Left; publications, legislative and political campaigns., Jul 26, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: LeSueur, Mieridel Description: Minnesota depression radicalism, 1930s., May 1, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Name: Lewis, Alfred Baker Description: Socialist Party, New England region, 1910s- 1940, civil rights movement, 1940s-60s., Sep 8, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Name: Lilja, Fred Description: Immigration; life as itinerant miner, lumber worker and fisherman, 1910s; activities of Finnish-American Left in Monessan, Pa., 1920s-1950., Jun 28, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Lillian, N. Description: Brooklyn College, National Students' League, Medical Bureau of Aid to Spanish Democracy, New York, 1930s., May 19, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Name: Luisa Description: United Electrical Workers Local 431, Emerson Electric Co., Jersey City., May 19, 1982 (Box 1)
    tape#: 2 U2N
  - Name: Lustig, James Description: Union activities of Hungarian-American Left in fur-leather and electrical workers, 1920s-40s; Lustig's role in strikes; black- listing in 1950s and work on Henry Wallace's farm; work on Uj Elore and Hungarian-American Word, 1950s-present., Oct 20, 1982 (Box 1)
    tape#: 1 U2N
- M
  - Name: Magil, A.B. Description: Background in Yiddish culture, Philadelphia; life on the Daily Worker, 1920s, self-denial of Yiddish cultural activities for "broader field"., Oct 31, 1980 (Box 1)
    tape#: 3 U2N
  - Name: Magli, Vito Description: Background as high school supporter of Vito Marcantonio in New York; youth leader of Marcantonio movement; editor of Communist Italian-language paper, L'Unita, its support in mining regions and cities, 1940s-50s; retirement to Florida and reflections., May 15, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Magner, Mary Description: Bridgeport (Connecticut) Socialist Party, recollections of executive secretary of Socialist Mayor Jasper McLevy, 1940-1957., Jan 26, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Name: Maisel, Robin Description: Socialist Workers Party, late 1960s-70s; work experience in print shops; influence of parents' radical convictions and activities., May 4, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Name: Manford, Julius, a.k.a. Morty Description: Gay rights, Aug 6, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Margolin, Julius, Description: Food Workers Industrial Union; National Maritime Union; WW II no-strike pledge; Communist view of Trotskyism; Korean War. 1930s-50s., Dec 30, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Marsh, Alice Description: Socialist Party, 1930s; the struggle between Communists and Socialists in the Teachers Union., Feb 24, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Name: Martocchia, Anthony and Lamantia, Philip Description: Martocchia's anarchist origins in Italy and his anti-fascist activities in Chicago, 1920s; San Francisco/Las Gatos anarchist group, 1930s-50s; meeting with Philip Lamantia, 1940s; Lamantia's sense of support from older anarchists, 1940s; importance of Malatesta for Martocchia. Anarchist publications today., Oct 31, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Name: Matteotti Club Description: Reunion of Rhode Island activists in Sacco-Vanzetti Defense Campaign, 50 years after execution; discussion of defense activities, mostly by Luigi Nardella., 1977 (Box 1)
  - Name: McGrath, Tom Description: Literature in the 1930s Left; poetry and the Popular Front; Cold War and Left Culture., Mar 9, 1977 (Box 2)
    tape#: 1 U2O
  - Name: McKinney, Ernest Rice Description: Biographical interview with important black radical born in 1886, covering his youth and education, activities as Socialist (1910s), Communist (1920s), "Musteite" (1930s), "Shachtmanite" (1940s); mentions Unemployed Leagues, A. Philip Randolph., Feb 25, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Name: McLevy, Vida Description: Bridgeport (Connecticut) Socialist Party, career of her husband Jasper McLevy as Socialist Mayor of Bridgeport, 1933-1957., Nov 4, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Name: Medem Jewish Socialist Group/Forum on Jews and the Left Description: Discussion by Paul Buhle and Arthur Liebman of Jews and the Left in the US, 1890- present, with questions from audience and response., Feb 26, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Name: Melvin-Gerson, Sophie Description: Russian background, being jailed due to strike NOT IN OHAL GUIDE, Mar 13, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Name: Michelson, Claire Description: Participating in strikes and being arrested NOT IN OHAL GUIDE, Oct 29, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Name: Migas, Nick Description: Unionism and politics in Gary, Indiana, 1930s-40s; ethniciy, race and radicalism; Wisconsin National Farmers Union, 1950s., Mar 15, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Mitchell, John Description: Packinghouse Workers, Communist Party, Boston, Mass., 1940s-50s., Mar 30, 1981 (Box 1)
    tape#: 2 U2O
  - Name: Mizara, Eva Description: Lithuanian-American radicalism 1920s-1960s, Jun 24, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Name: Mother Audley Moore Description: Youth in New Orleans; Marcus Garvey movement, 1920s; Communist Party in Harlem, 1930s; her break with the Communist Party., 1972 (Box 1)
  - Name: Mother Audley Moore Description: Communist Party in Harlem, 1930s, Dec 23, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Name: Morgan, Anna Description: Boston childhood; life in Cuba, 1917; Chicago in the Depression, Communist Party in Champaign, Ill.; Indianapolis, Columbus, Ohio, 1930s-50s; reflections., Jan 22, 1981-Jan 29, 1981 (Box 2)
    tape#: 4 U2O
  - Name: Moskowitz, Gussie Description: Hungarian-American, Furriers Union, Communist Party, Jun 4, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Name: Munckton, Elma Description: Experiences in Finland, 1890s, for a girl on a farm; emigration and life in U.S. for domestic workers; Finnish-American Left in Bay Area, 1920s-60s., Nov 9, 1983 (Box 2)
- N
  - Name: Nadelman, Morris Description: Yiddish Anarchist origins in Russia; Yiddish Anarchist activities in Los Angeles, 1920s- present; Rudolf Rocker circle and Rudolf Rocker's personality; activities in Arbeter Ring; fundraising for victims of Spanish Civil war., Apr 8, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Name: Nardella, Luigi Description: Speech delivered to Rhode Island Labor History Forum, unemployed movement in R.I., 1930s., Mar-78 (Box 2)
    tape#: 3 U2O
  - Name: Nelson, Steve Description: Labor-radical background in 1920s; Chicago unemployed activities; activities in anthracite coal districts; Popular Front and Spanish Civil War., 1981 (Box 2)
    tape#: 2 U2P
  - Name: Norrick, Joseph and Ruth Description: Origins of radicalism in Indiana coal mining traditions, 1910s-20s; Norrick's role in 1930s-40s Left; perspective on problems of "Americanizing" Communism to the U.S.; Ruth Norrick's background in Terre Haute, Indiana; meeting with Eugene Debs; literary life in New York, 1930s; Cold War blacklisting from UN Children' agency; journalism since., Mar 15, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Name: Norris, Clarence Description: "Scottsboro Boys" case recalled by one of nine defendents, including roles of Inter- national Labor Defense and NAACP; and circumstances of his recent pardon., Feb 25, 1981 (Box 2)
    tape#: 1 U2P
  - Name: Novick, Paul Description: Novick's attitude toward Yiddish culture; employment by the Groysser Kundes magazine as humorist; gravitation to Morgen Freiheit., Jan 20, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Name: Nowak, Stanley Description: Polish-American Left in Detroit, 1930s; cigar workers; UAW; American Slav Congress; Polish-American Left organizations, 1910s- 1920s; Poland today., Mar 30, 1983 (Box 2)
    tape#: 3 U2P
- O
  - Name: O'Brien, Marjorie Description: Background in Wisconsin and University of Wisconsin Trotskyist circle; activities in 1940s; attitude toward C.L.R. James and Johnson-Forest Tendency., May 7, 1983 (Box 2)